redbull.tv 2017-05-18

# Privacy | Red Bull TV

If you are a user from other than the United States, please see the policies below under B.:

If you are a user from the United States, see the following policies: 

A. Privacy Policies for users from the United States:

1\. Introduction

1.1 This Red Bull Privacy Policy ("Policy") sets out how Red Bull Media House GmbH, whose offices are at Oberst-Lepperdinger-Str. 11-15, 5071 Wals near Salzburg, Austria (hereinafter “Red Bull”, "we", "us", "our") collects and processes information about you when you, among other things, visit our website, use our applications on mobile phones or other consumer electronic devices, apply for a job, access our social media experiences or other experiences where this Policy is posted (the "Properties"). By continuing to use any of these Properties, you consent to your information being collected, processed/or and shared in accordance with this Policy. 

2\. Information we collect 

2.1 We collect two types of “Information.” Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information. Personally Identifiable Information means any information that itself identifies you or would easily enable someone to contact and/or identify you, such as your name, social security number, email address or phone number. Non-Personally Identifiable Information refers to all other information about you that you may provide to us or that we may collect from you. 

2.2 You may actively give us Information about yourself when you, among other things, use one of our Properties, create an account ("Account") with us, subscribe to a newsletter, purchase a game, product or service, participate in a contest or sweepstakes, respond to a customer survey, email us, post in a public forum and/or use our chat/message functionality. The Information that you provide may include your name, gender, date of birth, email address, telephone number, delivery address, billing address and payment information, and login and password. Note also that Information you disclose in public chat and similar forums is accessible by anyone, including third parties not bound by this Policy.

2.3 When you visit one of our Properties, we may also automatically collect, among other things, the following Information even if you have not actively given it to us: your IP address, log-in information, location information (for example, via GPS or WiFi), browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, information about your visit including the URL clickstream to, through and from one of our Properties, products and/or content you viewed or searched for, download errors, length of visits to certain pages and page interaction, and in the case of our mobile applications, the other applications you have downloaded and how you use those applications. We collect Information automatically through the use of various technologies, including through "cookies", which is explained further below in Section 8. 

2.4 We acquire Information from other trusted sources (including, for example, business partners, advertising networks, search information providers, credit reference agencies and social media), and from other Red Bull entities and affiliates, to update or supplement the information you provided or we collected automatically. Note that this includes Information from your social media account when you grant us access to your social media account in connection with, for example, creating an Account with us. Where permitted by law, we may combine this information we receive from other sources, and with information you give to us or that we collect about you. 

2.5 If you have created an Account on one of our Properties, you may be able to obtain a copy of the Personally Identifiable Information we collect from you via your Account and correct, amend, or delete Personally Identifiable Information that is inaccurate. You may also close your Account altogether. Before we are able to respond to your request, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide further details about your request. We will endeavour to respond within an appropriate timeframe and, in any event, within any timeframes required by law.

2.6 It is your responsibility to ensure that you submit true, accurate and complete Information via your Account and keep it up to date. You may also update your Personally Identifiable Information by contacting us through the contact details provided below. Please make sure to include your name, username, and post code in your initial correspondence; this helps us protect the details and preferences on your Account from unauthorized access.

2.7 If you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a registered user of any of our Properties, California law permits you to request and obtain removal of content or information you have publicly posted. To make such a request, please send us a detailed description of the specific content or information by going to http://energydrink-us.redbull.com/privacy-contact-form. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested.

2.8 In addition, if you are a California resident California law also permits you to request the Personal Information we collect and third parties that received the Personal Information for the third parties' direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. To make such a request, please send us a detailed description of the specific content or information by going to http://energydrink-us.redbull.com/privacy-contact-form. 

3\. How we use, share and disclose your information

3.1 We may use your Information for the purposes of enabling you to use our Properties, enabling us to fulfil orders you make (such as for products, services or newsletters), to send you marketing materials, and provide personalized content and experiences. We may also use the Information we collect: (i) to administer our Properties for internal purposes, including troubleshooting purposes; (ii) optimize or improve our products, services, operations, and Properties; (iii) as part of our effort to keep our Properties safe and secure; (iv) to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; (v) to communicate with you about your Account or transactions with us and send you information about features on our Properties or changes to our policies; (vi) to provide you with advertising based on your activity on our Properties and on third-party sites and applications; (vii) to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Properties about goods or services that may interest you or them; and (viii) to detect, investigate and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal. 

3.2 We may share your Information with our Red Bull entities and affiliates and the third parties described in this Policy. We may also share your Information with third parties: (1) when it is necessary to involve a third party service provider to facilitate or offer our services; (2) when explicitly requested by you (e.g., with social media networks); (3) when required by a court order or any legal or regulatory requirement; (4) in connection with the sale or transfer of a business; (5) to enforce our Terms of Use; (6) to ensure the safety and security of our users, consumers and third parties; and (7) to protect our rights and property and the rights and property of our users and third parties.

4\. User choice, including how to opt in or opt out from direct marketing

4.1 We, and selected third parties with whom we share your Information, may use your Information for direct marketing purposes, including to provide updates, newsletters, events or other communications that we think may interest you. Where required by law, your prior consent will be obtained before we send direct marketing. In any event, we will offer you the option to unsubscribe from electronic marketing materials. 

5\. Data Security and Retention

5.1 We apply appropriate security measures aimed at protecting your Personally Identifiable Information that is under our control from unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification or disposal, but we can offer no guarantees or warranties related to such protection and are not responsible for such unauthorized activity. We will notify you in compliance with applicable law regarding any data breach. Where you have a password that enables you to access our Properties, you are responsible for keeping this password secure and confidential.

5.2 Please be advised that we may retain some personal information after you delete your Account, for example if necessary to meet our legal obligations or for tax and accounting purposes. 

6\. Links to other websites

6.1 Where we provide links to other websites or services, we do so for information purposes only. The other websites and services are outside our control and are not covered by this Policy. If you access other websites or services using the links provided, the operators of these websites and services may collect Information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. 

6.2 On some pages of our Properties, third parties that provide content, services, applications or plug-ins through our Properties may directly track your use of content, applications and plug-ins or customize content, services, applications and plug-ins for you consistent with their privacy policies, which may differ from ours.

7\. Use of Properties by minors

7.1 The features, programs, promotions and other aspects of our Services requiring the submission of personally identifiable information are not intended for children. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 15. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 15 and believe he or she has disclosed personally identifiable information to us please Contact Us at http://energydrink-us.redbull.com/privacy-contact-form. A parent or guardian of a child under the age of 15 may review and request deletion of such child's personally identifiable information as well as prohibit the use of that information. 

8\. Online Tracking - Cookies and other technologies

8.1 A cookie is a text file containing small amounts of information that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your computer as a tag that distinguishes your computer but does not name you. Some of our Properties use cookies to better serve you when you return to the Property. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies; however, if you do this, some of the features of our Properties may not work properly. You can also reject certain cookies served through Properties by opting out on the website of the third party placing the cookie, which you can identify through your browser. 

8.2 We may use or allow third parties to use tracking technologies (e.g., cookies, beacons, tracking pixels) to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information about your browsing activities so that online advertisers can serve you advertising that better reflects your interests (“Interest-Based Ads”). For more information on Interest-Based Ads or to stop use of tracking technologies for these purposes, go to www.aboutads.info or www.networkadvertising.org. 

8.3 We may also use local shared objects, sometimes known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Our advertisers and third-party service providers also may use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies, please go to http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html. If you disable Flash cookies, you will not have access to many features that make your guest experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. 

8.4 Finally, Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of sites. Web beacons may involve the transmission of Information directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its privacy policy. We may use Web beacons to bring together Information we collect about you. 

8.5 We may use third party tools to make the advertising we show you on our Properties and/or our partner websites more relevant and interesting to you. For this purpose, we use cookies, flash cookies, web beacons or similar technologies to collect information about your browsing behaviour, and deliver interest-based ads to you. 

8.6 Certain browsers may offer you the option of providing notice to websites that you do not wish for your online activities to be tracked for preference based advertising purposes (“DNT Notice”). For a variety of reasons, we do not take any action based on browser based DNT Notices. Rather, if you do not wish to participate in preference based advertising activities, you should follow the simple opt-out processes identified above.

9\. Changes to the Policy

9.1 This Policy was last updated on May __, 2016. A notice will be posted on our Properties for 30 days whenever this Policy is changed in a material way. By continuing to use our Properties you confirm your acceptance of the relevant changes.

10\. Questions about this Policy

If you have a question, concern or complaint about this Policy or our handling of your information, you can contact us by going to http://energydrink-us.redbull.com/privacy-contact-form. 

B. Privacy Policies for users form other than the United States:

(Last Update: May 2016)

Introduction

This Red Bull Privacy Policy ("Policy") sets out how Red Bull Media House GmbH, whose registered offices are at Oberst-Lepperdinger-St. 11-15, 5071 Wals near Salzburg, Austria, (hereinafter “Red Bull”, "we". "us", "our") collect and process information about you when you use our mobile applications and games ("Apps"). By continuing to use our Apps, you consent to your information being processed in accordance with this Policy.

Information we collect and how we use it 

What personal information does the App collect and why? When you download and use the Apps, you may be provided with an option to create a user account ("Account"). The information that you provide when setting up your Account may include your name, email address, telephone number and Account username. If you create an Account with us, you will also have a unique password which enables you to access your Account. Alternatively, you can also create an Account using your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ credentials. 

You do not have to log-in to an Account to use the App, however, if you do not we may not be able to personalize your experience, for example we may not be able to save your game progress and you may lose any in-App purchases that you have made once you uninstall the App. You will however be provided with a unique user identification number, which will be visible to you in the App and which you can use for support requests. Any preferences that you make while not logged-in will be saved to your device and may not be accessible by us.

When logging into your Account or using the App, you will give us information that can identify you ("personal information") and you consent to us using for the purposes set out in this Policy. Please note that where you have provided consent in relation to any processing carried out by us through the App, you may withdraw this consent at any time, in which case (unless we have an alternative justification for such processing) we will stop this processing. You can exercise this at any time by contacting us and our contact details are set out in paragraph 14, and you should be aware that once your consent is withdrawn and the App is uninstalled, you will lose your game progress and any in-App purchases that you have made. 

When you use our Apps, we may use your personal information to create specialised recommendations to enhance your user experience. This can include recommending content for you to watch based on your viewing history or Facebook "likes" and interests (as applicable). We will not collect your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ username or password, but we may collect details from these websites that confirm whether you are logged-in to the App using your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ accounts (a "token"). This information is used to access and extract certain information about you from your Facebook, Twitter or Google+ profiles to enhance your user experience and provide you with meaningful content. This is information that you make available to the public on your profile. We do not access your personal account settings.

If you make any in-App purchases, we will also collect your location and payment information. Please note that we will not store your payment information, this will be done via a third party payments company. 

The personal information that you provide to us will also be used for the purposes of enabling you to use our Apps, for administrative and troubleshooting purposes (to determine which parts of the App should be improved) and in order for us to send you marketing materials (should you opt in to receiving marketing material from us). As explained in Section 2.8 below, we may also use this information for further purposes when combined with other data we collect about you.

Information we collect automatically. When you use our Apps, we may automatically collect the following information: your log-in information, location information, operating system version, screen resolution, device processing power and memory, download errors, user behaviour (such as length of App use) and any number of unique identifiers associated with your mobile device, for example an IMEI address (a unique number assigned to mobile phones that is used by GSM networks to help them identify valid mobile devices). We collect information automatically through the use of various technologies, including "unique device identifiers" ("IDs"), and this is explained further below. 

We use the information we collect automatically: (i) to administer our Apps for internal operations including troubleshooting purposes; (ii) to ensure that content from our Apps is presented in the most effective manner for you and your devices; (iii) as part of our effort to keep our Apps safe and secure; (iv) to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; and (v) to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Apps about goods or services that may interest you or them.

Information we receive from other sources. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other services we provide on the Apps, or from other Red Bull entities and affiliates. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them (including information that is publicly available).

Where permitted by law, we may combine this information we receive from other sources, including from social media websites (as set out above in paragraph 2.4), with information you give to us and information we collect about you, including ID information. We may use this information and the combined information for learning more about your preferences as our customer, for enhancing your user experience on our Apps and for providing you with information, content and offerings tailored to your needs.

How we share and disclose your information

We may share your information with our Red Bull affiliates at http://www.redbull.com/en/affiliates for the purposes outlined in this Policy and with the third parties listed in this Policy. We may also share your information with third parties when: (1) it is necessary to involve a third party service provider in order to facilitate or extend our services; (2) explicitly requested by you (e.g. with social media networks); (3) required by a court order or any legal or regulatory requirement; (4) in connection with the sale or transfer of a business for fulfilling our obligations to you; (5) to enforce our Terms and Conditions; (6) to ensure the safety and security of our users, consumers and third parties; and (7) to protect our rights and property and the rights and property of our guests and third parties.

How to opt in or opt out of direct marketing

We, and selected third parties, may use the information you give us on our Apps for direct marketing purposes to provide updates; newsletters; events; or other communications that we think may interest you. Where required by law, your prior consent will be obtained before sending direct marketing. In any event, we will offer you the option to unsubscribe in every communication sent.

Analysis and Advertising

We use third party tools, including the Turn Audience Suite and related tools provided by Turn to make the advertising we show you on our Apps and/or our partner apps more relevant and interesting to you. For this purpose, we use IDs or similar technologies to collect information about your user behaviour (see sections 2.5 and 2.6 above) and deliver interest-based ads to you. For further information about the use of data by Turn please click on the following link: http://www.turn.com/trust/privacy-guidelines. You may opt-out at any time from the collection and use of your data by Turn by clicking the following link: http://www.turn.com/trust/consumer-opt-out. 

IDs and other technologies

We collect information automatically through the use of IDs. An ID is a specific string of numbers and letters (a "character string") which is assigned to your device, but does not name you. The ID allows us and our selected third parties to track your behaviour when you use the App. Almost every App uses ID technology. IDs serve a number of purposes such as remembering your preferences, and generally improving your user experience. 

IDs may tell us, for example, whether you have used our Apps before or whether you are a new user. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see through the Apps are more relevant to you and your interests. This functionality makes IDs extremely useful to improve your user experience. 

What types of IDs do we use?

We use different categories of IDs (such as Adverting IDs and Analytics IDs) which fulfil important functions within the App. You may disable these IDs via your mobile device settings or by using the links provided in the list below, however, there are two broad categories of IDs. IDs that are essential for the operation of Apps, also known as Strictly Necessary IDs, enable features without which you would not be able to use Apps as intended. Your consent is not required for the use of Strictly Necessary IDs, which is why Strictly Necessary IDs cannot be disabled using the features of or the links on App. However, you have the option to completely disable IDs in your device at any time. The other category of IDs are IDs which, in strictly legal terms, are not essential to use the Apps. Nevertheless, these IDs do still fulfil important functions. You may disable any of these IDs via your mobile device settings or by using the links provided in the list below. However, if you do so this may prevent certain features or services of the Apps from working properly and therefore affect your experience whilst using the Apps. The list below shows the full range of IDs we may use with our Apps, however most of our Apps will not use all of these IDs. Whether or not an ID is used in each App will be based on developer preferences. 

The specific types of IDs and other technologies that may be served through the Apps are described below: 

Type of ID Who serves them Click on the following links to block the IDs

Strictly Necessary IDs 

These IDs are necessary to provide you with services available through Apps and to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas. Without these IDs, services you have asked for, like a personalised App function, would not be possible. 

Red Bull 

Not applicable.

Advertising IDs. 

These IDs are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same advertisements from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests. Vungle http://vungle.com/privacy/

Double Click for Publishers http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/

Upsight http://www.upsight.com/pricing/privacy-policy/

Unity Ads http://unity3d.com/legal/privacy-policy

Fyber https://www.fyber.com/privacypolicy-en.html

MediaBrix https://mediabrix.com/ad-services-privacy-policy/

AppLovin https://www.applovin.com/privacy

InMobi http://www.inmobi.com/privacy-policy/

Facebook Exchange https://www.facebook.com/business/a/online-sales/facebook-exchange

Bidswitch http://www.bidswitch.com/

Analytics IDs. 

These IDs collect information that is used, either in aggregate form to help us understand how the Apps are being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or, to help us customize the Apps for you. This information will not be stored on your device. It will also be used for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Apps, compiling reports on Apps activity for Red Bull App operators and providing them other services relating to App activity and usage. Flurry http://www.flurry.com/legal-privacy/terms-service/flurry-analytics-terms-service

Urbanairship http://urbanairship.com/legal/privacy-policy

Webtrekk http://www.webtrekk.com/en/index/dataprivacy.html

Google Analytics http://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en

Localytics http://www.localytics.com/privacy-policy/

Upsight http://www.upsight.com/pricing/privacy-policy/

Crashlytics https://try.crashlytics.com/terms/

Leanplum https://www.leanplum.com/privacy

Social Media Plug-ins. 

On some parts of the Apps, third parties that provide applications through our Apps may insert their own technology ("plug-ins") in order to track the success of their applications or customize applications for you. For example, when you share a game score using a social media sharing button on an App (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, or Google Plus), the social network that has created the button will record that you have done this. Because of how these plug-ins work, we cannot access this technology, nor can the third parties access the data in the IDs used by us. Some parts of our Apps may also contain embedded content, such as video content from YouTube, and these sites may set their own IDs or plug-ins. Facebook If you want to prevent this, you must first log out of your Facebook account before activating the Facebook plug-in, or alternatively disable all Facebook settings on your device when using the App. https://www.facebook.com/policy.php 

Twitter Log out of your Twitter account before activating the Twitter plug-ins, or alternatively and then disable all Twitter settings on your device when using the App. 

http://twitter.com/privacy

Google+ Do not log in to the App using your Google+ or Google account. 

http://www.google.com/intl/policies/policies/privacy/

The Apps may make use of GPS tracking in order to provide you with location-based functions and the Apps may also access the photos and videos that you store on your mobile device to allow you to upload videos and photos for use within the Apps. Finally, the Apps may use push notifications to send you notifications, for example the App may send you a notification when another player beats your high score. When you first use the App, you will be asked if you want to activate these functions in your settings menu. If you choose not to activate these functions, or to deactivate them later on, you may not be able to use the App's full scope of services. 

You can also refuse advertising IDs in the settings of your respective operating system. If you need assistance with this, please email us at the address set out at paragraph 14.

Since your ID and plug-in opt-out preferences can be stored on your device, please also note that if you use a different device, you will need to renew your opt-out choices. 

Data Retention

We will not retain your information for longer than is necessary for our business purposes or for legal requirements. However, please be advised that we may retain some information after you have closed your Account with us, for instance if doing so is necessary to meet our legal obligations, such as retaining the information for tax and accounting purposes. 

Please also note that any information held by third parties will be subject to the terms of their privacy policy and that we will have no control over that information.

Your rights

If you wish to obtain a copy of personal information that we hold about you, please contact us at the address set out in paragraph 14 below. Before responding to your request, we may ask you to verify your identity and to provide further details about your request. We will endeavour to respond within an appropriate timeframe and, in any event, within any timescales required by law.

If you have chosen to have an Account then you can access the personal information we hold about you via your Account following the process as set out in paragraph 9.1above to obtain a copy of it and to correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate. You can also close your Account at any time by contacting us at the address set out in paragraph 14.

It is your responsibility to ensure that you submit true, accurate and complete information to your Account and keep it up to date. You may also update your personal information by contacting us, using the contact details provided below. Please make sure to include your name, username and post code in your initial correspondence; this helps us protect the details and preferences on your Account from unauthorised access.

Information security

We apply appropriate security measures to protect your personal information that is under our control from unauthorised access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification or disposal. All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers. 

However, please note that no transmission over the Internet or any public network can ever be guaranteed completely secure, and we cannot accept any liability for any security compromise to transmissions over such networks. Where you have a password, which enables you to access our Apps, you are responsible for keeping this password secure and confidential.

Internet-based transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal information necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. While we generally store all of the personal information that we collect about you through our Apps in your region (for example for European visitors, in the European Economic Area), it is possible that your personal information will be transmitted to parties outside your region (where data protection laws may be different). If such transfer happens, we ensure that it takes place in compliance with contractual or other measures to protect the information.

Use of this Apps by minors

If you are aged 15 or under, please get your parent's/guardian's permission before you provide information to us via our Apps. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with information and, in the event that they do so, we will cease to process their information as soon as we find out. 

Changes to the Policy

You may find the latest version in the Privacy area under the settings menu of the App. We reserve the right to review and revise this Policy from time to time, in particular to satisfy the requirements of providers of platforms for the distribution of applications. We will inform you about any such change and we will provide you with a then current version of the Policy ("New Policy"). 

Questions about this Policy

This App is maintained by the Red Bull Media House GmbH. If you have a question, concern or complaint about this Policy or our handling of your information, you can contact us by email on privacy@at.redbull.com.

To unsubscribe from the newsletter, click the unsubscribe link in the respective newsletter email.

Consent

By installing and using this App and accepting the terms and conditions you expressly consent to Red Bull processing any personal information you provide to use through this App, as set out in this Privacy Policy, including the processing of your personal data by our service providers. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at the address set out in paragraph 14 above.

If you do not consent to Red Bull processing any personal information through this App, as set out in this Policy, you should uninstall and not use the App.
